God still loves us, and so he pursues us. He wants a relationship with us. And then that brings us to the second book in the Bible, the book of Exodus. God's people find themselves in Egyptian slavery, and God rescues them from their slavery just as God has rescued us in Christ.
It's also the season you're in right now because you're in the wilderness. You're in between, which is why you can perhaps at times feel like I'm alone. Why do I feel lonely in this season? So are you ready to jump into the book of Numbers?
If you look up in your scripture earlier, you'll see in verse 46 that there's 600,000 plus people who were counted in the census. Now, that is all men 20 years of age and older, so women and children weren't counted. And so scholars estimate that it's about 2 million or 2.5 million people who left Egyptian slavery, which this is amazing. It shows the promises of God always being fulfilled.
so that no wrath will fall on the Israelite community. The Israelites did everything just as the Lord had commanded Moses. This is God's word. Okay, this is really fascinating, and I'm gonna apply this to you because this has everything to do with you because you're in the wilderness right now.
And maybe that's what you thought I would challenge you to do today. You showed up at church, you're watching online, you're like, okay, Eric's going to ask me for God to have a bigger place in my life. That's not at all how God instructs his people to live in the wilderness. He is not asking to be a part of your life.
9, in between chapter 1 and chapter 9, there's more census data and there's some of the law that is given to God's people. So clearly as we walk through the book of Numbers, we're not looking at every single verse, but we're looking at the major themes in this book to see how we live in the wilderness. And you're gonna see some other really insightful themes in this text. This is chapter 9, verse 15.
Up to above the tent, above the tabernacle of the testimony, and they would see during the day a cloud, and at night it appeared to be a pillar of fire. All they had to do was look up, and they would be reminded that God was with them. And then when they were told to move, to move the tent to another location, it was really simple when to figure out. The most complex movement in the ancient world, 2.5 million people, was decided by one simple question, is the cloud moving?
According to the scripture, you actually have it better than they had it because you don't look over there to a tent to see a cloud above the tent. You are the tent. Now, if you are new to the Christian faith, this may sound crazy, but understand this is what us Christians believe that when we placed our faith in Jesus, God sent the spirit of the living God to live within us. We are now the temple.
The Thames River, and he offered to buy the bridge. They dismantled the bridge piece by piece and shipped it to Lake Havasu, Arizona, and that bridge was rebuilt. Same bridge, reinforced, but it's actually a bridge from London. And there's all kinds of statues about it and photos, and it's an iconic picture there.
And the temple of God, it is fascinating. Here's what scripture gives you the thread of the temple. When God created Adam and Eve, this is the beginning of the Bible. He placed them in the garden and he walked with them in the cool of the day.